HASAN AL KHALED

IT Project Manager

- +880 1717077776
- hasanalkhaled@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/hasanalkhaled



Summary

Experienced computer science graduate with over 15 years of expertise in developing and managing web development projects. My roles have ranged from web developer to team leader and head of engineering. Known for strong ethical values, I consistently strive for moral excellence in all aspects of my work.

Experience (15+yrs)

Education (CS Grad)

Head of IT

Icon Tech | Oct 2023 - present

- Spearhead research and development efforts to drive technological innovation and maintain market competitiveness.
- Manage the full project lifecycle, including requirements gathering, solution design, development, testing, deployment, and post-launch support.

E-Commerce Project Manager

RPoribar Co. Ltd | Mar 2022 - Sep 2023

 Successfully managed end-to-end implementation of in-house e-commerce system, ensuring on-time delivery and meeting client requirements.

IT Project Manager

Shomadhan Platform | Jan 2021 - Jan 2022

- Led and managed IT projects from initiation to successful completion, ensuring adherence to scope and timelines.
- Monitored project progress, tracked milestones, and communicated updates to stakeholders and team members.

BRAC University

B.Sc. in Computer Science | 2003 - 2009

- Graduated, 124 Credits.
- Thesis: B2B Web Portal

Notre Dame College

Higher Secondary Cert. | 2000 - 2002

- Science
- First Division
- Elective Computer Studies

Dhaka Residential Model School

Secondary School Cert. | 1998 - 2000

- Science
- First Division Star
- Elective Computer Studies

Training

BRAC University

Professional Skill Dev Program | 2009

Experience

DevOp Manager

OnoNic Systems | Mar 2019 - Nov 2020

- Managed cloud-based infrastructure (e.g., AWS, Azure, GCP) and implemented infrastructure as code (IaC) practices.
- Demonstrated strong project management skills, ensuring timely delivery

IT Project Manager

Green Technologies | Oct 2015 - Dec 2018

- Led and managed IT projects from initiation to successful completion, ensuring adherence to scope, budget, time.
- Carrying out the production and delivery of products and/or services on a regular basis.

Project Manager

Graphic People | Sep 2013 - Apr 2014

- Manage and oversee offshore digital production projects to ensure successful execution and delivery.
- Measure project performance using appropriate systems, tools and techniques.

Team Leader

Panacea Systems | Aug 2012 - Aug 2013

- Manage development teams by conducting daily stand ups, ensuring sprints are completed on time and removing impediments.
- Work with development team to troubleshoot dev and prod environment, performance tune and optimize code

Webmaster

Jobs-ICT pvt ltd | Dec 2009 - Jul 2012

- Manage and maintain websites, ensure they are up-to-date, secure, and functioning optimally.
- Monitor website performance, implementing necessary updates and improvements.

Skills

- Time Management
- Collaboration
- Agile Project Management Scrum
- System Analysis and Design
- Front-End Design
 - Photoshop, Illustrator
 - Basic Image Customization
- Front-End Development
 - HTML, CSS, Javascript
- · Back-End Development
 - PHP, Asp.Net, C#, Java
 - · Wordpress, Codeigniter, MVC
- Database Design & Management
 - o MySQL, MSSQL, Oracle
- Version Control GIT
- · Web Deployment
- Web Server Management
 - Apache
 - Debian
- Digital Marketing
 - SEO, SMM, PPC

Projects

- Offshore Digital Production Management
- Website Design & Development
 - E-Commerce
 - Portfolio
 - Business
 - Restaurant
 - Travel
 - Blog
- Web Application Development
 - Customer Relationship Management
 - Point of Sale
 - Human Resource Management
 - Inventory Management
 - Ticket booking System
 - Scholarship Management System
- Web Server Management
- Digital Marketing Management
- Dedicated Server Management
- Virtual Private Server Management

Personal Information

Language Proficiency

• Father's Name: Aba Khaled Rashid Ali

• Mother's Name: Shilpi Qureshi

• Date of Birth: 16th May, 1985

• Religion: Islam

• Nationality: Bangladeshi

• Marital Status: Married

• Address: 34/B East Noyatola, Moghbazar

• Extra Activities: Train, Run, Swim, Bike, Combat

English

Reading - High

Writing - Medium

Speaking - Medium

• Bengali

• Reading - High

Writing- High

• Speaking - High

Reference

Bob Wilson

Regional Coordinator | Coffey International

• Email: Bob_Wilson@southasiascholarship.org

· Address: Baridhara, Dhaka

Relation: Professional

Mumit Khan

Chairperson, CSE Dept | BRAC University

• Email: mumit@bracuniversity.ac.bd

• Address: Mohakhali, Dhaka

· Relation: Academic